<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/atom.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/atom.css" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
	<title>MISSOURI VALLEY AMBULANCE</title>
	<updated>2017-03-07T12:17:07-06:00</updated>

	<subtitle>Missouri Valley Ambulance is the inane ramblings and various projects of a gadget geek, Apple lover, and keyboard wonk.</subtitle>

	
		
		<author>
			
				<name>Morganspeck</name>
			
			
			
		</author>
	

	<link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />

	<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator>

	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2017-03-07-Blog-Theme</id>
			<title>Blog Theme</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2017-03-07-Blog-Theme" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog Theme" />
			<updated>2017-03-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Morgan</name>
					
					
						<email>blog@missourivalleyambulance.com</email>
					
					
						<uri>/Morgan</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Today I'm going live with a new theme for the blog. I'm really excited about the new look, and even more excited about the new functionality that the new theme offers. I loved the old look and feel, but it was time for a facelift. There has also been a lot more I'd like the site to be able to do - the new theme can do it.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2017-03-07-Blog-Theme">&lt;p&gt;Today I’m going live with a new theme for the blog. I’m really excited about the new look, and even more excited about the new functionality that the new theme offers. I loved the old look and feel, but it was time for a facelift. There has also been a lot more I’d like the site to be able to do - the new theme can do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Theme’ is a misnomer in a lot of ways though - this is more like an entirely new site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since its inception 2 years ago, the blog has ran on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;, running the theme ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://deanattali.com/beautiful-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Beautiful Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;’. The new blog also runs Jekyll, and is based on ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://phlow.github.io/feeling-responsive/&quot;&gt;Feeling Responsive&lt;/a&gt;’ by &lt;a href=&quot;http://phlow.de/&quot;&gt;Phlow&lt;/a&gt;. The core technology is the same, but there is a lot more going on under the hood with Feeling Responsive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling Responsive proved to be an excellent basis for the site. I’ve spent the past month making significant changes to the base Feeling Responsive theme, getting it dialed into something I’m really pleased with. By default, Feeling Responsive is a portfolio site with blog elements. I’ve spent many hours changing that default into a dedicated blog - including changes to the organization structure of the site, and how content is displayed and used. The theme as I have it now is suited to my workflow and how I want to blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy digging into technical projects, getting down to the nuts and bolts of how something works, so this site refresh has been really enjoyable for me. If it weren’t for Open Source projects like this and services like Github Pages, I probably wouldn’t have a site. I’m thankful that developers are out there to build this stuff for weirdos like me to play with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new theme is significantly more sophisticated, with more an entirely new file structure, and significantly more powerful CSS driven by &lt;a href=&quot;http://foundation.zurb.com/&quot;&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. The result gives the site many new ways to display content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;layouts&quot;&gt;Layouts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog now has 3 different layouts for content. Posts listed on the main page all use the same formatting, but the page for each post can display content in different ways as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tech/2017-02-06-My-Mailserver-Is-On-Fire&quot;&gt;Normal Page&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;This layout is the default for most posts. It displays content in the same width as on the main page. If the page has a header image, that is displayed in fullsize. &lt;a href=&quot;/tech/2017-02-06-My-Mailserver-Is-On-Fire&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016-06-29-Storm-Season&quot;&gt;Fullwidth Page&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;This layout is just like it says on the tin - fullwidth. This layout uses more horizontal space on the page, and will be used for posts where I want to give more size and focus for the content, especially pictures. &lt;a href=&quot;/2016-06-29-Storm-Season&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/videos/2016-02-10-1-Da-Comrade-Vhere-Ve-Are-Goink-Ve-Vont-Need-Roads&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;While the first two layouts are just slightly different versions of eachother, the Video layout is something entirely different. The video layout uses a white-on-black colorway and displays a fullwidth video, with a thin column for text. The layout really emphasizes the video content, and looks just killer. &lt;a href=&quot;/videos/2016-02-10-1-Da-Comrade-Vhere-Ve-Are-Goink-Ve-Vont-Need-Roads&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;headers&quot;&gt;Headers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old blog just displayed content the same way, whether on a post’s dedicated page, or on the main page. The new site has several different ways of playing with headers. If I choose to use a header, on the main page it is displayed a thumbnail, and as a full sized image on the post’s page. Backgrounds and colors can also be added behind the header image if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Header as seen on homepage&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/gELj85X.jpg&quot; style=&quot;-webkit-filter: drop-shadow(5px 5px 5px); filter: drop-shadow(5px 5px 5px);&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;hr width=&quot;75%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Header as seen on post page&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/VvrKASs.jpg&quot; style=&quot;-webkit-filter: drop-shadow(5px 5px 5px); filter: drop-shadow(5px 5px 5px);&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;better-typography&quot;&gt;Better Typography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site now uses better looking fonts, and can display it in more powerful ways. For headers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Volkhov&quot;&gt;Volkhov&lt;/a&gt; is used. For post content, the sans-serif &lt;a href=&quot;https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Lato&quot;&gt;Lato&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;blockquotes&quot;&gt;Blockquotes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockquotes now support citations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I think if you do something and it turns out pretty good, then you should go do something else wonderful, not dwell on it for too long. Just figure out what’s next.
&lt;cite&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inline-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Inline Code Blocks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than being limited to block code, the new site also supports &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;inline code displays like this one&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve long wanted footnotes on the site. With Feeling Responsive as a base, I can now include them. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;galleries&quot;&gt;Galleries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I’m really excited for (and what was the driving reason for building a new site) is Galleries. On most Jekyll based sites, one is limited to the features offered by Markdown and simple HTML. The new site uses Foundation to do great things, including galleries. I’m super jazzed to use this going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
	&lt;ul class=&quot;clearing-thumbs small-block-grid-4&quot; data-clearing=&quot;&quot;&gt;
		
		
		
		
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/Zgsvx8L.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-caption=&quot;Apple Extended Keyboard II + Alps64&quot; src=&quot;http://imgur.com/Zgsvx8L.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		
		
		
		
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/90lPEjR.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-caption=&quot;Planck&quot; src=&quot;http://imgur.com/90lPEjR.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		
		
		
		
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/qzGSMVX.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-caption=&quot;Blue Alps64&quot; src=&quot;http://imgur.com/qzGSMVX.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		
		
		
		
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/oD6D3DY.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-caption=&quot;Clueboard&quot; src=&quot;http://imgur.com/oD6D3DY.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		
		
		
		
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/beTVvQP.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-caption=&quot;Zenith Data Systems Keyboard&quot; src=&quot;http://imgur.com/beTVvQP.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		
		
		
		
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/rl9kPom.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-caption=&quot;Golbat&quot; src=&quot;http://imgur.com/rl9kPom.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		
		
		
		
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/izdoAmD.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-caption=&quot;Apple M0110&quot; src=&quot;http://imgur.com/izdoAmD.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		
		
		
		
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/hnrxQZw.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-caption=&quot;Modified Jelly Comb Numpad&quot; src=&quot;http://imgur.com/hnrxQZw.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;categories--metadata&quot;&gt;Categories &amp;amp; Metadata&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site now supports categories and tagging. I’m not making use of tagging, but I will be using Categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/apple/&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/keyboards/&quot;&gt;Keyboards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tech/&quot;&gt;Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posts that are assigned to a category also have navigation at the bottom of their pages to other posts in the same category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/k9D3Mcw.jpg&quot; style=&quot;-webkit-filter: drop-shadow(5px 5px 5px); filter: drop-shadow(5px 5px 5px);&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Posts now have enhanced metadata. Previously only the date was displayed, now pages can have authors as well. At the moment it’s just me writing for the site, but if I have any guest authors in the future, I will be able to cite &amp;amp; link to them more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;archive--teasers&quot;&gt;Archive &amp;amp; Teasers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site now has a dedicated &lt;a href=&quot;/archive/&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt; of all posts on the site. The archive also includes teasers about each post’s content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/Gjj12io.jpg&quot; style=&quot;-webkit-filter: drop-shadow(5px 5px 5px); filter: drop-shadow(5px 5px 5px);&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-functions&quot;&gt;Other Functions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Feeling Responsive theme also has a ton of other great functionality for displaying content. In preparing this new site, I needed to convert all the old posts for use with the new site. There is so much untapped functionality here. The existing posts use some of it, but I’m really excited to make use of as many of these new features as I can with future posts on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Made you look.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="tech" />
			
			

			<published>2017-03-07T00:00:00-06:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/2017-03-06-iOS-vs-Desktop-Security</id>
			<title>iOS vs Desktop Security</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/2017-03-06-iOS-vs-Desktop-Security" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iOS vs Desktop Security" />
			<updated>2017-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Morgan</name>
					
					
						<email>blog@missourivalleyambulance.com</email>
					
					
						<uri>/Morgan</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Great explanation from Matthew about the large attack surface presented by a modern desktop machine, and how it compares to mobile devices that were built with security and limited application power in mind. The piece can hopefully explain to the layuser some of the mindfulness that's needed to remain secure. </summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017-03-06-iOS-vs-Desktop-Security">&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/matthew_d_green&quot;&gt;Matthew Green&lt;/a&gt; in a piece called &lt;em&gt;Secure Computing For Journalists&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m going to devote this post to providing the world’s simplest explanation of why, in the threat model of your typical journalist, your desktop machine isn’t very safe. And specifically, why you’re safer using a modern mobile device — and particularly, an iOS device — than just about any other platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great explanation from Matthew about the large attack surface presented by a modern desktop machine, and how it compares to mobile devices that were built with security and limited application power in mind. The piece can hopefully explain to the layuser some of the mindfulness that’s needed to remain secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He puts it best here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Classical (desktop and laptop) operating systems were designed primarily to support application developers. This means they offer a lot of power to your applications. An application like Microsoft Word can typically read and write all the files available to your account. If Word becomes compromised, this is usually enough to pwn you in practice. And in many cases, these applications have components with root (or Administrator) access, which makes them even more dangerous.
&lt;br /&gt;
Modern phone operating systems like Android and iOS were built on a different principle. Rather than trusting apps with much power, each app runs in a “sandbox” that (mainly) limits it to accessing its own files. If the sandbox works, even a malicious application shouldn’t be able to reach out to touch other apps’ files or permanently modify your system. This approach — combined with other protections such as in-memory code signing, hardware secret storage and routine use of anti-exploitation measures — makes your system vastly harder to compromise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2017/03/05/secure-computing-for-journalists/&quot;&gt;via Cryptography Engineering&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Typed on ErgoDox Test Board&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
			

			<published>2017-03-06T00:00:00-06:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/videos/2017-03-01-Nintendo-Switch-Unboxing</id>
			<title>Nintendo Switch Unboxing</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/videos/2017-03-01-Nintendo-Switch-Unboxing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nintendo Switch Unboxing" />
			<updated>2017-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Morgan</name>
					
					
						<email>blog@missourivalleyambulance.com</email>
					
					
						<uri>/Morgan</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary></summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/videos/2017-03-01-Nintendo-Switch-Unboxing">&lt;p&gt;I haven’t owned a Nintendo Console since the SNES. My first reaction when I saw the first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f5uik5fgIaI&quot;&gt;Switch promo&lt;/a&gt; was: I want one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept and execution here looks great. I haven’t been following the Switch too closely since the reveal, but I’ll be keeping my eye on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main concern is the accessories. Seems like a lot is required outside of what comes in the main box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.loopinsight.com/2017/02/24/nintendo-switch-unboxing-initial-impressions/&quot;&gt;via Loop Insight&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Typed on Macbook&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="videos" />
			
			

			<published>2017-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/apple/2017-02-27-Sharing-iCloud-Notes</id>
			<title>Share Notes With iCloud</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/apple/2017-02-27-Sharing-iCloud-Notes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Share Notes With iCloud" />
			<updated>2017-02-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Morgan</name>
					
					
						<email>blog@missourivalleyambulance.com</email>
					
					
						<uri>/Morgan</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>I learned just yesterday that it's possible to share notes (from iOS/macOS' built-in Notes app) with others via iCloud. I've been aware of this functionality in Reminders for some time now, but I'm glad to know that it's present in Notes as well.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/apple/2017-02-27-Sharing-iCloud-Notes">&lt;p&gt;I learned just yesterday that it’s possible to share notes (from iOS/macOS’ built-in Notes app) with others via iCloud. I’ve been aware of this functionality in Reminders for some time now, but I’m glad to know that it’s present in Notes as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend has long maintained a shopping list, and I’ve always needed to defer to her to add items to the list. Now with iCloud notes sharing we’re both able to contribute to the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steps to share a note are super simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h5&gt;Make a note of course, then tap the plus person icon.&lt;/h5&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RSRgd4G.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 50%; height: 50%&quot; /&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h5&gt; Determine how to share the link. Your recipient must have an iCloud account. Obviously sharing via SMS or email is best for this.&lt;/h5&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/UFHCs36.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 50%; height: 50%&quot; /&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h5&gt;Send the invite.&lt;/h5&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/AsYbG91.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 50%; height: 50%&quot; /&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party on the other side will see your note, and when tapping on it, the note will automatically open in Notes.app and you’ll have fast syncing shared notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If in the future you need to add more people to the list, or remove someone’s access, just tap the plus person icon - people can be added, removed, or sharing can be stopped entirely from here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/MmKzIyx.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 50%; height: 50%&quot; /&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Typed on Octopage&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="apple" />
			
			

			<published>2017-02-27T00:00:00-06:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/apple/2017-02-22-Apple-Park-Theater</id>
			<title>Theater At Apple Park</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/apple/2017-02-22-Apple-Park-Theater" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Theater At Apple Park" />
			<updated>2017-02-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Morgan</name>
					
					
						<email>blog@missourivalleyambulance.com</email>
					
					
						<uri>/Morgan</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Apple is opening its new campus 'Apple Park' in April.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/apple/2017-02-22-Apple-Park-Theater">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/vllGFwa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple is opening its new campus “Apple Park” in April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Steve would have turned 62 this Friday, February 24. To honor his memory and his enduring influence on Apple and the world, the theater at Apple Park will be named the Steve Jobs Theater. Opening later this year, the entrance to the 1,000-seat auditorium is a 20-foot-tall glass cylinder, 165 feet in diameter, supporting a metallic carbon-fiber roof. The Steve Jobs Theater is situated atop a hill — one of the highest points within Apple Park — overlooking meadows and the main building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a fitting tribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macrumors.com/2017/02/22/apple-park-steve-jobs-theater/&quot;&gt;via Macrumors&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/newsroom/2017/02/apple-park-opens-to-employees-in-april.html&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Typed on MacBook&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="apple" />
			
			

			<published>2017-02-22T00:00:00-06:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/keyboards/2017-02-09-Kinesis-Countoured-Model-110</id>
			<title>Kinesis Contoured Model 110</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/keyboards/2017-02-09-Kinesis-Countoured-Model-110" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kinesis Contoured Model 110" />
			<updated>2017-02-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Morgan</name>
					
					
						<email>blog@missourivalleyambulance.com</email>
					
					
						<uri>/Morgan</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>A few days I added a Kinesis Countoured Model 110 to my collection. The predecessor to the Advantage and the Advantage 2, this model is over 20 years old.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/keyboards/2017-02-09-Kinesis-Countoured-Model-110">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/9pCXqKb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days I added a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kinesis-ergo.com/&quot;&gt;Kinesis&lt;/a&gt; Countoured Model 110 to my collection. The predecessor to the Advantage and the Advantage 2, this model is over 20 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the board for a steal on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/mechmarket&quot;&gt;/r/mechmarket&lt;/a&gt;. The seller said the board was not functional, producing only a beeping tone when plugged in. I figured that if all else, even if the built-in electronics weren’t functional that I could hand wire a matrix for it. Much to my surprise, using my PS/2 to USB adapter, the board is fully functional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/Ji4qdVn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kinesis is notable for its split design and ergonomic keywells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://missourivalleyambulance.com/ErgoDox_Omnibus&quot;&gt;ErgoDox&lt;/a&gt; derives much of its design from the Kinesis. Given that I’ve been using an ErgoDox as my daily driver at work for some time, using the Kinesis (albiet briefly) has proven fairly easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/eScRdV0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the side you can see the sculpting of the keywells. At first glance the sculpting appears haphazard, but in using it, the sculpting has proven to be brilliant. Clearly a lot of time and effort went into this design by the Kinesis engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/Cp1dn8M.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standard for Kinesis boards of the time, this one has plate mount &lt;a href=&quot;https://deskthority.net/wiki/Cherry_MX_Brown&quot;&gt;Cherry MX browns&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve never actually had a full board with browns before. They have a decent tactile bump, at 45g they’re light, but not too light. I did notice that they are quite scratchy, a common complaint about Cherry browns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/Q1G1waG.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, the board is over 20 years old. Tag dates it to circa 1993.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/jqEzns5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The I/O includes a PS/2 port for connecting to your PC, and 2 RJ-11 jacks used with optional foot switches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/o5IbEyE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cracking the board open, you can see how nuts the internal electronics are. By my count there are 7 PCBs inside, including the control electronics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/GQhuySV.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each keywell has this separated PCB design, terminating in a ribbon cable connected to the ‘main’ PCB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each side of the board also has 9 rubber membrane keys. These also terminate in a ribbon cable also connected to the main PCB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main PCB contains the keys for the thumb cluster. Each keywell PCB connects to it. The control electronics connect to this board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/AxiPTsd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main control electronics are pretty crazy. With jumper cables on several of the circuits. Not sure if this is due to errors during design, or if the jumpers are intentional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I can’t leave well alone, so I have modifications planned for this board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swap in Gateron switches.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I am thinking I’ll put in Gateron Browns, but I have a few different switches on order, so I may find myself installing Gatistotles or Zealios instead.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replace control electronics.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Given that the board is fully functional in its current state, I’d like to keep most of the existing PCBs in place. I’m hoping that I can sort out the pin configuration for the the keywell &amp;amp; membrane PCBs and wire them to a Teensy microcontroller, granting me modern USB connectivity, and full programability using TMK/QMK.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keycaps
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The stock sculpted DCS profile keycaps are great, but I may want to swap in all DSA profile or SA profile keys. I haven’t decided yet.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Typed on Blue Alps64&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="keyboards" />
			
			

			<published>2017-02-09T00:00:00-06:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2017-02-06-My-Mailserver-Is-On-Fire</id>
			<title>Everything Is On Fire</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2017-02-06-My-Mailserver-Is-On-Fire" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everything Is On Fire" />
			<updated>2017-02-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Morgan</name>
					
					
						<email>blog@missourivalleyambulance.com</email>
					
					
						<uri>/Morgan</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary></summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2017-02-06-My-Mailserver-Is-On-Fire">&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-background&quot;&gt;Some Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For two years now I’ve been managing my own email server built on &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailinabox.email/&quot;&gt;Mailinabox&lt;/a&gt;. I first built out the box in the wake of the Snowden revelations. It occurred to me that while Gmail does offer state-of-the-art encryption on their data at rest, it was entirely possible that Google would be subject to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_security_letter&quot;&gt;NSLs&lt;/a&gt; and definitely even mass data collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, email never really was designed for security, and unless you’re using PGP on every message it’s possible for &lt;strong&gt;anyone&lt;/strong&gt; listening on the wire to intercept messages as they come and go. Despite this, I felt it was best to decentralize myself - and thus remove as much of my digital identity from Google as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one’s threat model is a nation state actor there is no perfect defense against that, but it is possible to minimize the attack surface or at least make it a bit more difficult to be attacked or surveilled by being removed from as many centralized systems as possible. Thus, Mailinabox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-first-cracks-appear&quot;&gt;The First Cracks Appear&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was working perfectly until a few months ago - the build of my box predated Mailinbox’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org/&quot;&gt;LetsEncrypt&lt;/a&gt; integration, so I used an SSL cert issued by Comodo, and later WoSign. It was time to get myself moved off those options and on to LetsEncrypt (and in the wake of news of misdeeds by both Comodo and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/security/2016/10/24/distrusting-new-wosign-and-startcom-certificates/&quot;&gt;WoSign&lt;/a&gt; that was a good decision), however my box was being stubborn. Even if I SFTP’d into the machine and removed the existing certs, I couldn’t get any new certs to apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digging around the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.mailinabox.email/&quot;&gt;Mailinabox support forums&lt;/a&gt;, I found the proper script to invoke:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;./management/ssl_certificates.py --force
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that the LetsEncrypt cert was successfully applied, but weird stuff started happening to the server. Where once the status pages would show me all was well, I started getting failures instead. Despite the Status Checks page failing, the box was fully functional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I let the box continue to run until today - when it finally broke on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a LetsEncrypt certificate is issued, Mailinabox is &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to automatically renew the cert every 90 days. Today, my original LetsEncrypt cert expired. First warning was my phone telling me over and over again that it couldn’t connect to the mail server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;everything-is-on-fire&quot;&gt;Everything Is On Fire&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was unable to get new emails on my phone, and my desktop machine was making similar complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First step was to go out to the box’s admin page in an attempt to issue a new cert from the TLS console. In the interest of security, Mailinabox deployments enforce &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_Strict_Transport_Security&quot;&gt;HTTP Strict Transport Security&lt;/a&gt; (HSTS), which enforces SSL after you visit an encrypted site for the first time. HSTS is there to prevent a user from being exposed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Downgrade_attack&quot;&gt;downgrade attacks&lt;/a&gt;. In this case, with an expired certificate it prevented me from initiating a web connection with the site at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step was to SSH into the server and attempt the ssl_certificates.py script again - foiled! I got an error and it wouldn’t run. The server was telling me it had issues with OpenSSL - this was likely the result of my messing around with the server months earlier trying to force it to get a LetsEncrypt manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;hoped&lt;/em&gt; that an update would fix it, but unfortunately it did not. Just attempting to run the update to Mailinabox v0.21C didn’t work. Again I was encountering errors regarging OpenSSL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Time to build a new box&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I figured the only resolution was to build out a new box and attempt to migrate/recover all my data. Fortunately there is a guide on how to do that &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailinabox.email/maintenance.html#moving-boxes&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I ran a manual backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd mailinabox
sudo management/backup.py
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default Mailinabox does daily backups, but it was best to have a totally up-to-date backup. I also went into Mail, Contacts, and Calendar on my local machine and exported everything I had, just in case I was unable to restore from the backup on to the new box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was time to get the backup off the machine, so I fired up FileZilla and SFTP’d into the box. Per the Mailinabox instructions it’s neccessary to only grab &lt;em&gt;/home/user-data/backup/secret_key.txt&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;/home/user-data/backup/encrypted&lt;/em&gt;, but I opted to backup the entire &lt;em&gt;/user-data/&lt;/em&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/td2P77x.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then got started spinning up a new server with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/&quot;&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt;. It was necessary to rename my old droplet to &lt;em&gt;box.missourivalleyambulance.com&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;box.missourivalleyambulance.com.old&lt;/em&gt;. I was able to get the new box up and running quickly, including the Mailinabox install. The setup for this is actually down to a single curl command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -s https://mailinabox.email/setup.sh | sudo bash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the box was set up and fully configured, I went over to GoDaddy to set up the new IP address. One thing that’s brilliant about Mailinabox is that it hosts its DNS - so the only thing needed on the registrar’s end are the nameserver addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was time to SFTP into the new box, upload the &lt;em&gt;/user-data/backup/encrypted/&lt;/em&gt; folder, rename the existing &lt;em&gt;/user-data/&lt;/em&gt; folder to &lt;em&gt;/user-data-old/&lt;/em&gt; and run the restore command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd mailinabox/home
export PASSPHRASE=$(cat secret_key.txt)
sudo -E duplicity restore file:///home/backups/encrypted /home/user-data/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick server reboot, and the box was back to its original configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-fire-extinguished&quot;&gt;The Fire Extinguished&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timing for this failure was quite good actually. My domain was up for renewal with GoDaddy, expiring on 2/10. Since I was doing all this work with rebuilding the server today, I took the time go get my domain transferred over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hover.com/&quot;&gt;Hover.&lt;/a&gt; I’m just a few hours into being a Hover customer, but so far I’m pretty impressed. Their site offers step-by-step guides for how to get a domain released from GoDaddy and prepped for transfer to Hover. From the time I initiated the transfer until it was complete was just under an hour. Hover even automatically copied over all the nameserver glue records, so there was no fighting with those trying to get DNS working correctly with the mailserver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s funny - when I first got this mail server up and running 2 years ago it took me ages to get everything configured correctly. The whole process took me weeks. The largest barrier was getting the old Comodo SSL cert &amp;amp; DNS up and running correctly as I had no idea what I was doing. Today I experienced an unexpected failure of my mailserver, requiring a total rebuild. I was able to get it all resolved within a few hours. The largest parts of the rebuild today was just waiting for all &lt;em&gt;/user-data/&lt;/em&gt; directory information to transfer from one server to another, and waiting for DNS records to propagate after moving the server to a new IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Typed on ErgoDox Test Board&amp;lt;/p
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="tech" />
			
			

			<published>2017-02-06T00:00:00-06:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/apple/2017-01-17-z1-MacBook-Pro-Touchbar-Lockdown</id>
			<title>MacBook Pro Touchbar Lockdown</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/apple/2017-01-17-z1-MacBook-Pro-Touchbar-Lockdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MacBook Pro Touchbar Lockdown" />
			<updated>2017-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Morgan</name>
					
					
						<email>blog@missourivalleyambulance.com</email>
					
					
						<uri>/Morgan</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary></summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/apple/2017-01-17-z1-MacBook-Pro-Touchbar-Lockdown">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The new Touch Bar is often marketed as a gimmick, but one powerful capability it has is to function as a lockdown mechanism for your machine in the event of a physical breach. By changing a few power management settings and customizing the Touch Bar, you can add a button that will instantly lock the machine’s screen and then begin a countdown (that’s configurable, e.g. 5 minutes) to lock down the entire system, which will disable the fingerprint reader, remove power to the RAM, and discard your FileVault keys, effectively locking the encryption, protecting you from cold boot attacks, and prevent the system from being unlocked by a fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdziarski.com/blog/?p=6705&quot;&gt;via Jonathan Zdziarski&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only can you use Jonathan’s guide to lock down your MacBook Pro, but you can use it with all modern Macs using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/kb/PH18796?locale=en_US&amp;amp;viewlocale=en_US&quot;&gt;hot corner.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Typed on MacBook&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="apple" />
			
			

			<published>2017-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/videos/2017-01-17-Peeqo-The-GIF-Bot-Video</id>
			<title>Peeqo The GIF Bot Video</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/videos/2017-01-17-Peeqo-The-GIF-Bot-Video" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Peeqo The GIF Bot Video" />
			<updated>2017-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Morgan</name>
					
					
						<email>blog@missourivalleyambulance.com</email>
					
					
						<uri>/Morgan</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Following up on my post from last month, the creator of Peeqo has created a video about his GIF bot.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/videos/2017-01-17-Peeqo-The-GIF-Bot-Video">&lt;p&gt;Following up on a &lt;a href=&quot;/2016-12-10-Peeqo-The-GIF-Bot&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; from last month, the creator of &lt;a href=&quot;http://peeqo.com/&quot;&gt;Peeqo&lt;/a&gt; has created a video about his GIF bot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, more than before I realize the potential of this bot. Peeqo just &lt;strong&gt;exudes&lt;/strong&gt; charm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GIF response functionality is just a red herring to me. I see a bot like this, and I see personality, I see true potential for digital assistants. Systems like Siri and Echo make use of natural language understanding and machine learning, but they don’t have a lot of personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see great potential with Peeqo (or a similar bot) serving for the front end of an Echo or a Siri-like machine learning system. It’s fantastic. The developer plans to make the entire project open source, so there is a real possibility of seeing something like this available (even if it’s DIY) soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Typed on Blue Alps64&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
				<category term="videos" />
			
			

			<published>2017-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</published>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/2017-01-03-Kaby-Lake-CPUs</id>
			<title>Kaby Lake CPUs</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/2017-01-03-Kaby-Lake-CPUs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kaby Lake CPUs" />
			<updated>2017-01-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Morgan</name>
					
					
						<email>blog@missourivalleyambulance.com</email>
					
					
						<uri>/Morgan</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Intel's Kaby Lake CPUs were 'officially' launched today. Kaby Lake is a marked change from Intel's old Tick/Tock release schedule.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017-01-03-Kaby-Lake-CPUs">&lt;p&gt;Intel’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaby_Lake&quot;&gt;Kaby Lake&lt;/a&gt; CPUs were &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anandtech.com/show/10959/intel-launches-7th-generation-kaby-lake-i7-7700k-i5-7600k-i3-7350k&quot;&gt;‘officially’&lt;/a&gt; launched today. Kaby Lake is a marked change from Intel’s old Tick/Tock release schedule. They are instead moving to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anandtech.com/show/10183/intels-tick-tock-seemingly-dead-becomes-process-architecture-optimization&quot;&gt;Process/Architecture/Optimization.&lt;/a&gt; This ‘optimization’ release looks to offer few improvements over the 6th generation Skylake chips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Like the Devil’s Canyon refresh of Haswell, Kaby Lake desktop is but a mere clock speed boost disguised under the nomenclature of a new CPU generation. From an IPC standpoint, there’s nothing to tell Kaby Lake apart from Skylake. The one feature that might have proved interesting—support for Optane memory—is unlikely to be put to use until late 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/01/intel-core-i7-7700k-kaby-lake-review/&quot;&gt;via ArsTechnica&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Mac user, I mostly ignore Intel’s high-end CPU SKUs. That said, when happens in the high end can also have implications for their mobile chips. If Intel can’t iterate on their chips, Apple can’t ship machines with updated hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/eUFcX2R.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www-ssl.intel.com/content/www/us/en/processors/core/core-m-processors.html&quot;&gt;[Source]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;annotation mine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curiously, it’s worth noting that while the U series chips (like those used in the MacBook Air) are present in the Kaby Lake lineup, the only Y chip (used in the 12” Macbook) is an m3. Given this, I’m curious if the 12” Macbook will be updated any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Typed on ErgoDox Test Board&lt;/p&gt;
</content>

			
			

			<published>2017-01-03T00:00:00-06:00</published>
		</entry>
	
</feed>